

# JOSEPH KIM

# **INSTRUCTIONAL DESIGNER**

# **PROFILE**

I enjoy collaborating with subject matter experts to design clear, connective, cumulative, and career-oriented learning experiences for online undergraduate and graduate programs. My strengths entail making course development easier for busy faculty, promoting best practices of online course design, and systematizing processes for smooth user experiences.

# **EXPERTISE**

- Anticipating student and faculty confusion.
- Adapting to SME work styles.
- Learner-centered design.
- ADA and WCAG 2.1 accessibility guidelines.
- Presentation skills.

# **APPLICATIONS**

Adobe Audition Adobe Captivate Beautiful.ai Blackboard Collaborate Camtasia Canva Google Suite H<sub>5</sub>P HapYak Loom Microsoft Office Piktochart Screencastify Sony Vegas Video Editor Stencyl Visme WeVideo Zoom

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **INSTRUCTIONAL DESIGNER**

#### Azusa Pacific University | 10/2016 - Current

- Designed online courses for undergraduate and graduate programs.
- Applied UDL principles, Backwards Design, and Rapid Prototyping approaches.
- Ensured content clarity, organization, and accessibility standards.
- Provided training and troubleshooting for online course faculty.
- Special projects:
  - University-wide migration from Sakai to Canvas LMS.
  - Led project on converting 9-week courses to 8-weeks.
  - Migrated online course videos from Kaltura to YouTube.
  - Provided supervision for student workers' projects.

#### **ACADEMIC ADVISOR**

# University of Southern California | 2/2016 - 10/2016

- Supported online and on-campus students in academic, LMS, and technical needs.
- Coordinated student orientations, workshops, and commencements.
- Provided administrative support for 300+ students.

#### **ACADEMIC SUCCESS COACH**

## Los Angeles Pacific University | 6/2014 - 2/2016

- Guided online learners in Moodle LMS navigation and course walkthroughs.
- Advised working parents, active-military, and career-change students.
- Led New Learner Orientations for incoming online students.

#### LEAD ESL INSTRUCTOR

#### Dessin Design College | 10/2012 - 2/2014

- Taught beginner, intermediate, and advanced ESL classes.
- Supervised ESL instructors in curricula, instruction, and professional development.
- Revamped older curriculum to modern curriculum for all ESL levels.
- Wrote academic policies for BPPE & ACCET accreditation standards.

#### **TEACHING ASSISTANT**

#### Fuller School of Intercultural Studies | 9/2010 - 1/2012

- T.A. for Dr. Paul L. Jensen.
- Assignment grading and feedback for classes of 50-70 students.
- Management and correspondence in Moodle LMS.

#### **STRENGTHS**

- Input
- Intellectuion
- Context
- Harmony
- Connectedness

# LANGUAGES

- Fluent English
- Conversational Korean
- Novice Japanese
- Novice Spanish

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### DIRECTOR OF YOUTH, COLLEGE, & ADULT MINISTRIES

Torrance Good Shepherd Church | 10/2012 - 11/2015 Holy Gate Church | 2/2009 - 9/2010 Beautiful Lord Church | 12/2004 - 7/2006

- Curriculum development and instruction for middle school, high school, college, and adults.
- Supervised volunteers, team training, vision casting, community building.
- Managed budget of \$20,000 \$25,000, wrote accounting reports.
- Coordinated and led year-round events for multiple departments.

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

#### **CANVAS TRAININGS | 2017**

Assignments | Content Pages | Communication Tools Course Design Considerations | Leveraging Modules | Managing Quizzes

## LEARNING MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS

Canvas | D2L Brightspace | Moodle | Sakai

# AWARDS

EDWARD P MILLER SCHOLARSHIP | 2017 - 2018

KATE STAMPER WILHITE SCHOLARSHIP | 2016 - 2017

PRESIDENTIAL SERVICE AWARD | 2011

CHARLES E. FULLER SCHOLARSHIP | 2010 - 2011

KOREAN AMERICAN BUSINESS ASSOC. CERTIFICATE OF MERIT | 2010

# CONTACT

Mobile: 310.701.5842

Email: joseph.hn.kim@gmail.com LinkedIn: DesignForLearning

# **EDUCATION**

#### UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI

Ed.S., Information Science & Learning Technologies | Current, 4.0 GPA

#### FULLER THEOLOGICAL SEMINARY

M.A. Cross Cultural Studies | Completed 2012 M.A. Theology | Completed 2012

#### **CUNY CITY COLLEGE OF NEW YORK**

B.A. English | Completed 2007

# **PUBLICATIONS**

The Hanshaw Helm-Stevens Rapid Prototype Instructional Design Model: Examining the Dimensions of Structure and Dialogue within the Framework of Higher Education (2019).